Northern Shaw Striver Historic Survey Oral History Project OHP016
People's Archive, MLK Library
Northern Shaw Striver Historic Survey Oral History Project
1993
People's Archive, MLK Library
Koenreich, Jeff
OHP016
0.5 Linear feet
2 Boxes
Arrangement
Series 1: Transcripts Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews. Series 2: Interviews Materials in this series include master copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for all audio recordings.
Biographical / Historical
Jeff Koenreich (1954-2008) was born in Salem, Ohio and attended Ohio State University. He came to Washington, D.C. in 1978 and worked for the American Red Cross. As a community organizer, he helped found the Cardozo-Shaw Neighborhood Association and led an effort to restore the Lincoln Theatre.
Custodial History
Jeff Koenreich conducted these interviews in 1993 and the Tapes and transcripts were transferred to the Library in the mid 1990s. There is no deed of gift for this collection.
Scope and Contents
In 1993, Jeff Koenreich conducted these oral histories for the Library's Oral History Project. Residents of the Striver Section of the Shaw neighborhood were interviewed. Topics include the history of the neighborhood, childhood, family, segregation, the Civil Rights Movement, and the community.
Oral History; Segregation; Neighborhoods; Shaw (Washington, D.C.); Families; Civil rights movement
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews.
  - Lucille Johnson, 1993 August 27 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Helena Seegers, 1993 August 27 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Norman Wood, 1993 August 27 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ethel Bordley, 1993 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master copies of the oral histories on audio cassette. There are two copies for all audio recordings.
  - Lucille Johnson, 1993 August 27 (Box 2, Folder 16-01)
  - Helena Seegers, 1993 August 27 (Box 2, Folder 16-02)
  - Norman Wood, 1993 August 27 (Box 2, Folder 16-03)
  - Ethel Bordley, 1993 September 6 (Box 2, Folder 16-04)